Contact

PECHS Block 6, Karachi +92 3462573147 (Mobile) me.fahadsajid@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fahad-sajid (LinkedIn)

www.researchgate.net/profile/Fahad_Memon (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence (AI)
GenerativeAI
Machine Learning

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Urdu (Full Professional)
Sindhi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Registered Engineer (RE)
Introduction to Career Skills in
Software Development

Digital Technologies Case Studies: Al, IOT, Robotics, Blockchain

Fahad Memon

Tech Enabler | Blockchain Implementation | Engineer Pakistan

Summary

Always a student to learn, a Mechanical Engineer with a curious mind coupled with strong problem solving and research skills; an engineer inclined towards smart factories' processes, and efficient resource utilization areas; besides, dedicated towards technology driven solutions and their implementation; A true believer of circularity of resources.

A Blockchain enthusiast, avid for exploring its real world applications and implementation to collaboratively work in a trustless manner.

Experience

Pakistan Petroleum Limited
Trainee Engineer
March 2022 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

➤ Looking over day to day tasks comprising scheduled Preventive Maintenance of critical rotary

equipment which include Caterpillar Gas Gensets, Waukesha Gas Engine and Ariel Gas Compressor,

Quincy oil flooded screw type Instrument Air Compressors and various centrifugal and PD type pumps.

- ➤ Formulating Asset Integrity reports to monitor and effectively upkeep and enhance the longevity of plant accessories.
- ➤ Learned SAP PM module working of different transactions including material reservation, requisition
- and maintenance work orders (MWOs)
 ➤ Keeping track of Reliability, Accessibility and Maintainability (RAM) module

progress.

COBE Blockchain

to monitor the KPIs

Blockchain Researcher December 2021 - March 2022 (4 months)

Remote

Worked on COBE Blockchain's Yellow Paper, formulated its background study. It was based on a multi-factorial consensus mechanism to bring about a consensus, a crucial component of any blockchain.

Alkaram Textile Mills Pvt. Ltd Maintenance Trainee June 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 5 months) Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Maintenance Supervisor in Processing Dept of Alkaram Textile Mills, Landhi, Karachi.

- ✓ Preparing daily and monthly maintenance reports; analyzing recurring machine stoppages; evaluating MTBF, MTTR and other KPIs, and reporting to the Maintenance HOD.
- ✓ Formulating monthly Preventive Maintenance (PM) schedules in coordination with Production and Maintenance teams.
- ✓ Placing indent and issuance requests of required spares and managing the relevant machine spares through Oracle ERP panel.
- ✓ Worked on the project designing of Remodeling and Renovation of existing compressed air network of processing dept., designed new CAD layout and calculated BOM of the project.
- √ Worked on a project of energy efficiency to identify, analyze and contain
 wastage of

energy resources through faulty steam traps, inadequate or unavailable insulation on steam/condensate valves and pipes.

Dawlance Group of Companies Internship June 2019 - June 2019 (1 month)

Hyderabad, Pakistan

It was a brief one-week internship which comprised of different tasks of visiting and understanding working principles of every process responsible for the manufacturing of refrigerators from manufacturing of single parts to the final assembly line leading to the final product. And in the end, we had to submit a detailed report of the whole journey.

Gas Turbine Power Station (GTPS), Kotri Internship

Page 2 of 3

December 2017 - January 2018 (2 months)

Kotri, Jamshoro, Pakistan

It was a two-week internship of a Gas Turbine Power Plant in which I learnt about technical aspects of operations and maintenance (O&M) of Gas Turbines and other accessories and equipments. As it was also upgraded with the inclusion of steam turbine through combined cycle power plant (CCPP), that increased the efficiency of the plant, comparably.

Jamshoro Power Company Limited Internship January 2017 - January 2017 (1 month) Jamshoro, Pakistan

It was a one-month extensively technical internship based on practical learning experiences of different areas of power plant. It was a steam turbines equipped power plant with a total capacity of 880 MW. I learnt about the practical approach to operations and maintenance (O&M) of mechanical equipments like Turbines, Pumps, Heat-Exchangers, Cooling Tower Fans, Boilers, Draft fans and many more.

Education

Mehran University of Engineering and Technology

Master's degree, Environmental Engineering - USPCAS Water · (September 2021)

Mehran University of Engineering and Technology Jamshoro Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering (2016 - 2019)